Streib, Victor; Papers apap330
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
- Case Files, 1947-2012, Undated; 1; 19 cubic ft.
  - Sentenced Juveniles, United States, 1978-2007, Undated; 1.4; 6.9 cubic ft.
    - Texas: James Lawrence Roney, sentenced 1980, Undated (Box 7 (1-Case Files), Folder 52)
    - Texas: Jorge Salinas, sentenced 2002-08-29 (Box 7 (1-Case Files), Folder 53)
    - Texas: Chris Solomon, sentenced 1999, 2002 (Box 7 (1-Case Files), Folder 54)
    - Texas: Oswaldo Soriano Regaldo, sentenced 1994-05-06, 1999; 2002; 2005; Undated (Box 7 (1-Case Files), Folder 55)
    - Texas: Robert Springsteen, sentenced 2001-16-01, 2009; Undated (Box 7 (1-Case Files), Folder 56)
    - Texas: Son Tran, sentenced 2000-12-18, 2003 (Box 7 (1-Case Files), Folder 57)
    - Texas: Raul Villareal, sentenced 1994-09-21, 2003; Undated (Box 7 (1-Case Files), Folder 58)
    - Texas: Bruce Lee Williams, sentenced 199-12-16, 2002; Undated (Box 7 (1-Case Files), Folder 59)
    - Texas: Nanon Williams, sentenced 1995, 2002; Undated (Box 7 (1-Case Files), Folder 60)
    - Texas: Bobby joe Wills, sentenced 1985-05-31, 1988; 1993; Undated (Box 7 (1-Case Files), Folder 61)
    - Texas: Geno Wilson, sentenced 1999-12-10, 2002; Undated (Box 7 (1-Case Files), Folder 62)
    - Virginia: general, 1991 (Box 7 (1-Case Files), Folder 63)
    - Virginia: Chauncy Jackson, sentenced 1997-05-20, 2001; Undated (Box 7 (1-Case Files), Folder 64)
    - Virginia: Shermaine Johnson, sentenced 1998-08, 1999; 2002 (Box 7 (1-Case Files), Folder 65)
    - Washington: Michael Furman, sentenced 1990-03-06, Undated (Box 7 (1-Case Files), Folder 66)
  - Juveniles not sentenced to death, 1997, Undated; 1.5; 0.1 cubic ft.
    - State of Arizona vs. Felipe Petrona Cabanas, Undated (Box 7 (1-Case Files), Folder 67)
    - State of Delaware v. Michael Jones, Undated (Box 7 (1-Case Files), Folder 68)
    - State of Louisiana v. Clay Logan, 1997; Undated (Box 7 (1-Case Files), Folder 69)
    - State of Louisiana v. Weldon Williams and George Gillam, Undated (Box 7 (1-Case Files), Folder 70)
    - Commonwealth of Pennsylvania vs. Edward Batzig, Undated (Box 7 (1-Case Files), Folder 71)
    - Commonwealth of Pennsylvania vs. Hector Huertas, Undated (Box 7 (1-Case Files), Folder 72)
- Reference Materials, 1908-2012, Undated; 2; 3.8 cubic ft.
  Alphabetical by subject
  This series contains published works used by Streib in his professional duties as both a lawyer and a professor. Many of the articles are Streib's own writings, including his exhaustive and perpetually updated lists of every juvenile and woman on Death Row in America, as well as those who had been executed. This series also includes publications by the Legal Defense Fund and others who documented capital punishment cases. Source material for this finding aid is largely drawn from "A Tribute to Victor Streib," published in Ohio Northern University Law Review Volume XXXVII, no. 2 (2012), which can be found within this series.
  - Adolescence as a mental disability in capital punishment law by Victor L. Streib, 2000 January 8 (Box 1 (2-Reference Materials), Folder 1)
  - Adolescence, Mental Retardation, and the Death Penalty: The Siren Call of Atkins v. Virginia by Victor L. Streib, 2003 (Box 1 (2-Reference Materials), Folder 2)
  - Affidavit on Pennsylvania's Death Penalty for 16 year old offenders, 2003 (Box 1 (2-Reference Materials), Folder 3)
  - Affidavit on the Cruelty of Pennsylvania's Death Penalty for Juvenile Offenders, 2002 (Box 1 (2-Reference Materials), Folder 4)
  - Affidavit on the history of Arizona's Death Penalty for 16 year old offenders, 2001 (Box 1 (2-Reference Materials), Folder 5)
  - Affidavit on the history of Arizona's Death Penalty for 17 year old offenders, 2002 (Box 1 (2-Reference Materials), Folder 6)
  - Affidavit on the history of Louisiana's Death Penalty for 16 year old offenders, 2003 (Box 1 (2-Reference Materials), Folder 7)
  - American Bar Association Section of Criminal Justice Report to the House of Delegates, 1984 (Box 1 (2-Reference Materials), Folder 8)
  - American Executions of Female Offenders: A Preliminary Inventory of Names, Dates, and Other Information by Victor L. Streib, 1987 February 20 (Box 1 (2-Reference Materials), Folder 9)
  - American Executions of Female Offenders: A Preliminary Inventory of Names, Dates, and Other Information Third Edition by Victor L. Streib, 1988 April 6 (Box 1 (2-Reference Materials), Folder 10)
  - American Executions of Female Offenders: A Preliminary Inventory of Names, Dates, and Other Information Fifth Edition by Victor L. Streib, 1998 June (Box 1 (2-Reference Materials), Folder 11)
  - American Executions of Female Offenders: An Inventory of Names, Dates, and Other Information Sixth Edition by Victor L. Streib, 1998 August 14 (Box 1 (2-Reference Materials), Folder 12)
  - American Executions of Female Offenders: An Inventory of Names, Dates, and Other Information by Victor L. Streib, 2005 July 1 (Box 1 (2-Reference Materials), Folder 13)
  - American Journal of Criminal Law, 2003 (Box 1 (2-Reference Materials), Folder 14)
  - Amicus Curiae Brief of American Society for Adolescent Psychiatry in Support of the Petitioner by Victor L. Streib, 2002 (Box 1 (2-Reference Materials), Folder 15)
  - Avoiding the Juvenile Death Penalty in New York State by Victor L. Streib, 1991 April 5 (Box 1 (2-Reference Materials), Folder 16)
  - Bowers Files, Undated (Box 1 (2-Reference Materials), Folder 17)
  - Capital Punishment for Children Racism Regionalism and Excessiveness by Victor L. Streib, 1984 January 6 (Box 1 (2-Reference Materials), Folder 18)
  - Capital Punishment for Juveniles in the Criminal Justice System by Victor L. Streib, 1982 June 6 (Box 1 (2-Reference Materials), Folder 19)
  - Children Crime and Consequences: Juvenile Justice in America, 2003 (Box 1 (2-Reference Materials), Folder 20)
  - Dead Women Waiting: Who's Who on Death Row, 1998 (Box 1 (2-Reference Materials), Folder 21)
  - Death Penalty for Children: Only in America by Victor L. Streib, 1999 July 18 (Box 1 (2-Reference Materials), Folder 22)
  - Death Penalty for Children: The American Experience with Capital Punishment for Crimes Committed While Underage 18 by Victor L. Streib, 1983 (Box 1 (2-Reference Materials), Folder 23)
  - Death Penalty for Children: State Execution for Crimes Committed While Underage 18 by Victor L. Streib, 1982 March 24 (Box 1 (2-Reference Materials), Folder 24)
  - Death Penalty for Female Offenders 1973-1-1 - 2006-3-31 Issue #55 by Victor L. Streib, 2006 April 6 (Box 1 (2-Reference Materials), Folder 25)
  - Death Penalty for Female Offenders 1973-1-1 - 2006-6-30 Issue #56 by Victor L. Streib, 2006 July 3 (Box 1 (2-Reference Materials), Folder 26)
  - Death Penalty for Female Offenders 1973-1-1 - 2006-12-31 Issue #57 by Victor L. Streib, 2007 January 29 (Box 1 (2-Reference Materials), Folder 27)
  - Death Penalty for Female Offenders 1973-1-1 - 2007-3-31 Issue #58 by Victor L. Streib, 2007 April 3 (Box 1 (2-Reference Materials), Folder 28)
  - Death Penalty for Female Offenders 1973-1-1 - 2007-5-31 Issue #59 by Victor L. Streib, 2007 June 7 (Box 1 (2-Reference Materials), Folder 29)
  - Death Penalty for Female Offenders 1973-1-1 - 2007-6-30 Issue #60 by Victor L. Streib, 2007 July 13 (Box 1 (2-Reference Materials), Folder 30)
  - Death Penalty for Female Offenders 1973-1-1 - 2007-9-30 Issue #61 by Victor L. Streib, 2007 October 4 (Box 1 (2-Reference Materials), Folder 31)
  - Death Penalty for Female Offenders 1973-1-1 - 2007-12-31 Issue #62 by Victor L. Streib, 2008 February 18 (Box 1 (2-Reference Materials), Folder 32)
  - Death Penalty for Female Offenders 197301-1 - 2008-6-30 Issue #63 by Victor L. Streib, 2008 July 3 (Box 1 (2-Reference Materials), Folder 33)
  - Death Penalty for Female Offenders 1973-1-1 - 2009-6-30 Issue #64 by Victor L. Streib, 2009 June 30 (Box 1 (2-Reference Materials), Folder 34)
  - Death Penalty for Female Offenders 1973-1-1 - 2010-10-31 Issue #65 by Victor L. Streib, 2010 November 3 (Box 1 (2-Reference Materials), Folder 35)
  - Death Penalty for Female Offenders 1973-1-1 - 2011-12-31 Issue #66 by Victor L. Streib, 2012 January 17 (Box 1 (2-Reference Materials), Folder 36)
  - Death Penalty for Juveniles in Pennsylvania by Victor L. Streib, 1987 July 21 (Box 1 (2-Reference Materials), Folder 37)
  - Death Penalty for Juveniles in Washington by Victor L. Streib, 1987 February 26 (Box 1 (2-Reference Materials), Folder 38)
  - Death Penalty for Lesbians by Victor L. Streib, 1994 (Box 1 (2-Reference Materials), Folder 39)
  - Death Penalty for Women in North Carolina by Elizabeth Rapaport & Victor Streib, 2009 (Box 1 (2-Reference Materials), Folder 40)
  - Death Penalty in the news, 2000 (Box 1 (2-Reference Materials), Folder 41)
  - Death Row Vol. 1 No. 1, 1989 (Box 1 (2-Reference Materials), Folder 42)
  - Death Row Vol. 2 No. 2, 1992 (Box 1 (2-Reference Materials), Folder 43)
  - Death Row, 1993 (Box 1 (2-Reference Materials), Folder 44)
  - Death Row Vol. 4, 1994 (Box 1 (2-Reference Materials), Folder 45)
  - Death Row, 1995 (Box 1 (2-Reference Materials), Folder 46)
  - Death Row Vol. 6, 1996 (Box 1 (2-Reference Materials), Folder 47)
  - Death Row Vol. 7, 1997 (Box 1 (2-Reference Materials), Folder 48)
  - Death Row Vol. 8, 1998 (Box 1 (2-Reference Materials), Folder 49)
  - Death Row: Meet the Men and Women of Death Row, 1999 (Box 1 (2-Reference Materials), Folder 50)
  - Death Row USA, 1995 August 31 (Box 1 (2-Reference Materials), Folder 51)
  - Death Row USA, 1995 October 31 (Box 1 (2-Reference Materials), Folder 52)
  - Death Row USA, 1996 January 31 (Box 1 (2-Reference Materials), Folder 53)
  - Death Row USA, 1996 April 30 (Box 1 (2-Reference Materials), Folder 54)
  - Death Row USA, 1996 July 31 (Box 1 (2-Reference Materials), Folder 55)
  - Death Row USA, 1997 July 31 (Box 1 (2-Reference Materials), Folder 56)
  - Death Row USA, 1998 October 1 (Box 1 (2-Reference Materials), Folder 57)
  - Death Row USA, 1999 January 1 (Box 1 (2-Reference Materials), Folder 58)
  - Death Row USA, 1999 April 1 (Box 1 (2-Reference Materials), Folder 59)
  - Death Row USA, 1999 September 1 (Box 1 (2-Reference Materials), Folder 60)
  - Death Row USA, 2003 July 1 (Box 2 (2-Reference Materials), Folder 1)
  - Death Sentences and Executions for Juvenile Crimes, 1984-1986 (Box 2 (2-Reference Materials), Folder 2)
  - Death Sentences and Executions for Juvenile Crimes, 1987-1989 (Box 2 (2-Reference Materials), Folder 3)
  - Death Sentences and Executions for Juvenile Crimes, 1990-1992 (Box 2 (2-Reference Materials), Folder 4)
  - Death Sentences and Executions for Juvenile Crimes, 1993-1995 (Box 2 (2-Reference Materials), Folder 5)
  - Death Sentences and Executions for Juvenile Crimes, 1996-1998 (Box 2 (2-Reference Materials), Folder 6)
  - Death Sentences and Executions for Juvenile Crimes, 2000-2003 (Box 2 (2-Reference Materials), Folder 7)
  - Death Sentences and Executions for Juvenile Crimes, 2003 (Box 2 (2-Reference Materials), Folder 8)
  - Death Sentences and Executions for Juvenile Crimes, 2004 (Box 2 (2-Reference Materials), Folder 9)
  - Death Sentences and Executions for Juvenile Crimes, 2005 (Box 2 (2-Reference Materials), Folder 10)
  - Decline and Fall of Juvenile Capital Punishment: The Beginning of the End of a Scandalous American Practice?, 1988 March 12 (Box 2 (2-Reference Materials), Folder 11)
  - Defense Counsel in Juvenile Death Penalty Cases by Victor L. Streib, 2003 July 26 (Box 2 (2-Reference Materials), Folder 12)
  - "A Descriptive Profile and Socio-Historical Analysis of Female Executions in the United States, 1632-1997" by David V. Baker, 1998 (Box 2 (2-Reference Materials), Folder 13)
  - The Devil in Massachusetts by Marion L. Starkey, Undated (Box 2 (2-Reference Materials), Folder 14)
  - Ending the Execution of Juveniles by Victor L. Streib, 1987 February 18 (Box 2 (2-Reference Materials), Folder 15)
  - Ending the Death Penalty for Juveniles by Victor L. Streib, 2003 April 5 (Box 2 (2-Reference Materials), Folder 16)
  - Equal Justice For All?, 2005 (Box 2 (2-Reference Materials), Folder 17)
  - Watt Espy Research, 1987; 1992 (Box 2 (2-Reference Materials), Folder 18)
  - Watt Espy Research, 1983-1998 (Box 2 (2-Reference Materials), Folder 19)
  - Watt Espy Research, 1983-1998 (Box 2 (2-Reference Materials), Folder 20)
  - Executed Women Research - General, Undated (Box 2 (2-Reference Materials), Folder 21)
  - The Female Offender Bibliography, South Carolina, 1990 (Box 2 (2-Reference Materials), Folder 22)
  - "The Forgotten Population" ACLU, 2004 (Box 2 (2-Reference Materials), Folder 23)
  - Gassing the Bunny by Michael Mello, 1997 (Box 2 (2-Reference Materials), Folder 24)
  - Gendering the Death Penalty: Countering Sex Bias in a Masculine Sanctuary by Victor Streib, 2002 (Box 2 (2-Reference Materials), Folder 25)
  - Georgia's Death Penalty for Juvenile Offenders by Victor L. Streib, 2002 February 15 (Box 2 (2-Reference Materials), Folder 26)
  - Imposition of the Death Penalty in Arizona for Crimes Committed While age 17 or younger by Victor L. Streib, 1993 November 16 (Box 2 (2-Reference Materials), Folder 27)
  - Imposition of the Death Penalty in Florida for Crimes Committed While age 16 and younger, 1991 June 30 (Box 2 (2-Reference Materials), Folder 28)
  - Jackson AFF [Affidavit?], Undated (Floppy-disk 1)
  - The Juvenile Death Penalty: History of a Shameful Practice by Victor L. Streib, 2003 November 7 (Box 2 (2-Reference Materials), Folder 29)
  - The Juvenile Death Penalty in Pennsylvania by Victor L. Streib, 1992-1993 (Box 2 (2-Reference Materials), Folder 30)
  - The Juvenile Death Penalty in the United States and Worldwide, 1997 (Box 2 (2-Reference Materials), Folder 31)
  - Killing Kids for Justice: Capital Punishment for Young Offenders by Victor L. Streib, 1982 November 4 (Box 2 (2-Reference Materials), Folder 32)
  - "The Last Stop Women in the Electric Chair" by Mark Gado, 2001 (Box 2 (2-Reference Materials), Folder 33)
  - Legal Defense Fund Death Row, USA, 1977 January 18; 1983 August 20-1984 December 20 (Box 2 (2-Reference Materials), Folder 34)
  - Legal Defense Fund Death Row, USA, 1985 March 1-1986 December 20 (Box 2 (2-Reference Materials), Folder 35)
  - Legal Defense Fund Death Row, USA, 1987 March 1-1988 December 20 (Box 2 (2-Reference Materials), Folder 36)
  - Legal Defense Fund Death Row, USA, 1989 March 1-1990 September 21 (Box 3 (2-Reference Materials), Folder 1)
  - Legal Defense Fund Death Row, USA, 1991 January 21-1992 Spring (Box 3 (2-Reference Materials), Folder 2)
  - Legal Defense Fund Death Row, USA, 1992 Summer-1993 Spring (Box 3 (2-Reference Materials), Folder 3)
  - Legal Defense Fund Death Row, USA, 1993 Summer-1995 Spring (Box 3 (2-Reference Materials), Folder 4)
  - Moratorium on the Death Penalty for Juveniles, 1998 (Box 3 (2-Reference Materials), Folder 5)
  - Murder America by Jay Robert Nash, 1980 (Box 3 (2-Reference Materials), Folder 6)
  - "Murderess: A Study of the Women Execution in Britain Since 1843" by Patrick Wilson, 1971 (Box 3 (2-Reference Materials), Folder 7)
  - Ohio Northern University Law Review Vol. XXVI, No. 3, 2000 (Box 3 (2-Reference Materials), Folder 8)
  - Ohio Northern University law Review Vol. XXXVIII, No. 2 - A Tribute to Victor L. Streib, 2012 (Box 3 (2-Reference Materials), Folder 9)
  - Ohio Northern Magazine and Alumni Journal, 2005 Summer (Box 3 (2-Reference Materials), Folder 10)
  - An Overview of the Death Penalty for Juveniles by Victor L. Streib, 1987 June 30 (Box 3 (2-Reference Materials), Folder 11)
  - The Palace of Death or The Ohio Penitentiary Annex by H.M Fogle, 1908 (Box 4 (2-Reference Materials), Folder 1)
  - Prosecutorial Discretion in Juvenile Homicide Cases by Victor L. Streib, 2005 (Box 4 (2-Reference Materials), Folder 2)
  - Parade Magazine article - Tom Seligson, "Are They Too Young to Die?: Wayne Thompson is One of 44 Juvenile Criminals on Death Row" [2 copies], 1986 October 19 (Oversized 1, Folder 4)
  - Rare and Inconsistent, The Death Penalty for Women by Victor L. Streib, 2006 (Box 4 (2-Reference Materials), Folder 3)
  - Roper v. Simmons, 2004 October (Cd 1)
  - Scaffold and Chair: A Compilation of Their Use in Pennsylvania (1682-1962), 1963 (Box 4 (2-Reference Materials), Folder 4)
  - "Should Women Hang?" by Bernard O' Donell, 1956 (Box 4 (2-Reference Materials), Folder 5)
  - Standing Between The Child and the Executioner: The Special Role of Defense Counsel in Juvenile Death Penalty Cases by Victor L. Streib, 2003 (Box 4 (2-Reference Materials), Folder 6)
  - States Already Ending Juvenile Death Penalty by Victor L. Streib, 1988 June 30 (Box 4 (2-Reference Materials), Folder 7)
  - A Study Assesses Traits of Women Who Kill, 1986 (Box 4 (2-Reference Materials), Folder 8)
  - Supreme Court Application of Eighth Amendment Jurisprudence to Juvenile Death Penalty Cases by Victor L. Streib, 1989 November 11 (Box 4 (2-Reference Materials), Folder 9)
  - Testimony: The Death Penalty for Juveniles, Offered to the Committee on Courts and Criminal Code, Indiana House of Representatives, 1987 February 4 (Box 4 (2-Reference Materials), Folder 10)
  - Testimony: Death Penalty for Juveniles in Kentucky by Victor L. Streib, 1988 January 25 (Box 4 (2-Reference Materials), Folder 11)
  - Testimony: Death Penalty for Juveniles in Missouri by Victor L. Streib, 1989 February 22 (Box 4 (2-Reference Materials), Folder 12)
  - Testimony: Legislative Criteria Concerning the Death Penalty for Juveniles by Victor L. Streib, 1989 September 27 (Box 4 (2-Reference Materials), Folder 13)
  - Testimony on the Death Penalty for Juveniles offered to the Subcommittee on Criminal Justice Regarding House Bill 343 and Related Bills by Victor L. Streib, 1986 June 5 (Box 4 (2-Reference Materials), Folder 14)
  - Vertical File: Juvenile Death Penalty News Clippings, 1982; 1983; 1999; Undated (Box 4 (2-Reference Materials), Folder 15)
  - Patricia Wernert W.P. 8, Undated (Floppy-disk 2)
  - Women Lawfully Executed in the United States: A Preliminary Inventory of Names, Dates, and Other Information by Victor L. Streib, 1987 February 20 (Box 4 (2-Reference Materials), Folder 16)
  - Women Lawfully Executed Under State Authority by Victor L. Streib, 1985 February 23 (Box 4 (2-Reference Materials), Folder 17)
  - Women Who Died in the Chair by Wendell Brown, 1963 (Box 4 (2-Reference Materials), Folder 18)
  - Writ, 2004 Spring (Box 4 (2-Reference Materials), Folder 19)